Harshit Singh

+917905344236 | hs.7905344236@gmail.com | Gurgaon, Haryana

Summary

Hands on Experience in **developing**, **deploying** and **maintaining** software applications with proper **Authentication** and familiar with programming languages frameworks such as **Python Django**, Laravel and have a solid understanding of software development, **Machine learning** and **Data analysis** methodologies and best practices.

Github- github.com/harshitsingh003

Education

Vishveshwarya Group of Institutions | Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh Computer Science & Engineering | 07/2023

82.4% overall aggregate

Children Senior Secondary School | Azamgarh, Uttar Pradesh Class XII | 05/2019

Children Senior Secondary School | Azamgarh, Uttar Pradesh Class X | 05/2017

Experience

Benepik Technology Pvt Ltd | Gurgaon, Haryana Software Development Engineer | 12/2023 - Present

Working on existing Products of Benepik and Crafting Robust Solutions for Seamless Functionality of the Applications with proper Authentication and Authorization

Salesiinni I Mumbai, Maharashtra

Software Development Enginner | 08/2023 - 12/2023

Working on Php Laravel ,Python Django and created (Smarten) an end to end application alone which having strong validations and authentication , various backends mappings and through which specific role of Users and people can access the things at different Levels.

Link - https://salesjinni.in/smarten/login

Ikargos | Delhi, Delhi

Associate Software Engineer Trainee | 02/2023 - 05/2023

Responsible for creating apis in Laravel and Springboot, Optimization of functionalities, fixing bugs, created Dashboards for analysis, created machine learning models and integration

Simplify360 | Bengaluru, Kamataka Data Analyst Intem | 09/2022 - 01/2023

Figuring out **insights** from large chunks of **Hero Motocorp** Data, and created reports using Data mining and cleaning through Python

Skills

Python, Data Structures and algorithms, Django, Php Laravel, MySQL, Java, JQuery, Machine Learning, Docker, Git and Github, Elastic search, Html & Css

Certificates

Machine learning from Technex IIT BHU, Data Visualizations from Great Learning, Python Programming from Great Learning

Acheivements

Aspire Internship from Government of India in SRMS Unnao., Cultural and Sports head of VGI, Prime member of Peer-to-Peer group and T&P office Vgi, Cricket team Captain of VGI and winner of Zonal Tournament, Placement Coordinator

Projects

Smarten Project - This is basically a **web app** which helps in managing Admins, Dispatchers, Distributors, Sub-Distributors, Dealers, and Customers at different level of access, **authentication** and authorization of **SMARTEN GROUPS**

MicroX - This is a **Django Web App** which helps in getting jobs to small vendors like Watchman , tutors , Maids with the **interactive maps** which having Job Seeker and Job givers.